P.O. Box 233 Maine, NY 13802 (575) 224-0080

Robert Ross Peterson

http://robertpeterson.io contact@robertpeterson.io

SUMMARY

Twelve years of IT experience that includes consulting, development, architecture, and management. Hands-on professional who leads by example. Enjoys new technology and building elegant systems with best practices. Currently specialize in iOS / Android freelance projects.

EDUCATION

M.S. Computer Science, University of Florida B.S. Computer Engineering with High Honors, University of Florida Gainesville, FL

EXPERIENCE

Present

RESIDENT – Lama Foundation

Ouesta, NM



Remote mountain-based inter-faith spiritual community, sustainable ecosystem, and nonprofit retreat center Served as maintainer for off-the-grid solar system, computer systems administrator, and retreat program coordinator

2012 - 2015

HEALTHCARE IT MANAGER – Texas Health & Human Services (HHSC)

Austin, TX



Managed backend systems for Medicaid, SNAP Food Benefits, Prenatal Healthcare, and Affordable Care Act (ACA)

- Systems process benefits for 15% of Texas population or ~4.4 million
- Served as team leader for 8 staff members and various auxiliary consultants
- Through strategic hiring of talent, automation projects, and restructuring of team processes, transformed team from below average to most productive in department
- Designed security implementation for Texas/Federal ACA system using DES cryptography, LDAP, and DataPower XSLT

2012

CO-FOUNDER - parseix.com

Williamsville, NY



- Designed and implemented front-end of initial offering using HTML5, CSS3, jQuery, & Highcharts
- Successfully hired and created requirements documentation for visual designer

2010 - 2012

INTEGRATION ARCHITECT - IBM Tivoli

Austin, TX



Agile project lead responsible for ten engineers for Business Service Management offering

Contributions enabled successful launch of IBM product in 1Q 2012

2005 - 2010

IT CONSULTANT — IBM Websphere

Austin, TX

- Conducted business internationally for over 50 customers, many of which are Fortune 500 companies, in industries including financial, insurance, aerospace, energy, and retail
- Developed complex client solutions with a variety of technology including jQuery/Dojo Javascript, CSS, REST, JavaEE, SQL, XSLT, and Web Services



IT ANALYST — Boeing Integrated Defense Systems

St Louis, MO

Designed Oracle PL/SQL database application for F-16, F-18, C-17, & missile production

NOTABLE PUBLICATIONS



- Book: Persistence In the Enterprise, IBM Press, May 2008 (ISBN-0131587560)
- Book: WebSphere Application Server V6, IBM Redbooks, May 2005 (ISBN-0738490601)
- Bridging Web 2.0 and SOA with DataPower, WebSphere Technical Journal, September 2011
- Integrating WebSphere Service Registry with Tivoli, IBM developerWorks, December 2010
- Leverage Existing WAS J2EE Resources with Apache Geronimo, SYS-CON, May 2006
- US Patent 20090019421: Runtime Machine Supported Method Level Caching, January 2009
- US Patent 20080133538: Background File Sharing in Peer-To-Peer (P2P) File Sharing Network, June

NOTABLE CONFERENCE TALKS





- Tivoli and WebSphere Integration, IBM PULSE Conference, March 2012
- DataPower in a Web 2.0 World, IBM IMPACT Conference, May 2010
- Case Studies for WebSphere Service Registry, WebSphere Services Technical Conference, April
- Aspect-Oriented Programming with Eclipse for J2EE, WebSphere Technical Conference, March

ADDITIONAL DISTINCTIONS

- Texas HHSC Leadership Community Member, invited to leadership meetings and training
- IBM Master Inventor, title awarded for outstanding IP contributions to IBM
- IBM General Manager Award (among numerous others OTAA, Stock Awards, Bravo Awards)